Guide to the School Development Program, Child Study Center, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Audiovisual Materials, 1983-2000; Series IV
  - Comer-Rockefeller retreat, Sarasota, Florida
    - Police, community, and teachers meeting at Southside School, 1989 November 16; 2 (Box 73–74)
    - Comer retreat, 1989 November 17; 5 (Box 75–79)
    - Dr. Edwina Stanley and Mary Watts interviews, 1989 November 17; 1 (Box 80)
    - Southside B-Roll and Mary Watts interview, 1989 November 17; 1 (Box 81)
    - Dr. Fowler interview and B-Roll at Booker/Southside, 1989 November 17; 1 (Box 82)
  - Prince George's County
    - Food preparation, 1990 February 24; 1 (Box 83)
    - B-Roll and food Preparation, 1990 February 24; 1 (Box 84)
    - Chillum School and Pearson family, 1990 February 24-25; 1 (Box 85)
    - Pearson family and Devine Faith Church, 1990 February 25; 1 (Box 86)
    - Devine Faith Church, 1990 February 25; 1 (Box 87)
    - Pearson Family and teacher orientation, 1990 February 26; 1 (Box 89)
    - Unidentified, 1990 February 26; 1 (Box 90)
    - Teacher orientation, 1990 February 26; 3 (Box 91–93)
  - Comer process
    - Prince George's County
      - James Comer at Johnson Middle School, 1990 March 15; 3 (Box 98–100)
      - James Comer at Potomac High School, 1990 March 15; 2 (Box 101–102)
    - Sarasota II
      - Southside classrooms, 1990 April 24; 1 (Box 103)
      - District level meeting, 1990 April 24; 2 (Box 104–105)
      - Room tone for district level meeting, interview with parents from district School Planning and Management Team and exteriors, 1990 April 24; 1 (Box 106)
      - Parent teacher group, 1990 April 25; 2 (Box 107–108)
      - Parents group, Mary Watts interview and school exteriors, 1990 April 25; 1 (Box 109)
  - American Psychiatric Association, New York City
    - James Comer introduction at Solomon Carter Fuller award with cutaways and question and answer, 1990 May 14; 1 (Box 110)
    - Comer receiving American Psychiatric Association President's Award, 1990 May 14; 1 (Box 111)
  - Interview with James Comer, 1990 May 20; 2 (Box 113–114)
  - Comer School Development Program
    - Introduction by Hugh Price and part one of presentation by James Comer, 1990 November 13; 1 (Box 115)
    - Part two of presentation by James Comer, 1990 November 13; 1 (Box 116)
    - Introductions by Hugh Price, edited, 1990 November 13; 1 (Box 117)
  - Comer School Development Program series, segment 1 -- Mixed master by EVT Productions, Inc. [commercially produced], 1991 January 3; 1 (Box 118)
  - Interviews
    - Albert Solnit on how Yale Child Study Center was founded, 1990 April 26; 1 (Box 119)
    - Albert Solnit, Yale Child Study Center, New Haven, 1990 April 26; 1 (Box 120)
    - Stephen Signore, former principal of Martin Luther King School, with Martin Luther King School B-Roll, 1990 April 26; 1 (Box 121)
    - Ruth Wilson, former Martin Luther King School teacher, with stills and Martin Luther King School B-Roll, 1990 April 26; 2 (Box 122–123)
  - Brennan School B-Roll, 1990 April 27; 1 (Box 124)
  - Jackie Robinson Middle School
    - B-Roll and interview with Rene Holland, social service skills director, 1990 April 27; 2 (Box 125–126)
    - Breakfast
      - B-Roll, 1990 April 28; 1 (Box 127)
      - B-Roll and Parent Teacher Student Organization meeting with Principal Charles Warner, Linda DuBose, and Caroline Jackson, 1990 April 28; 1 (Box 128)
      - B-Roll with Principal Charles Warner, Linda DuBose, and other speakers, 1990 April 28; 1 (Box 129)
      - Discussion of parents' concerns and issues, 1990 April 28; 1 (Box 130)
      - Parent Teacher Student Organization workshop and interview with Linda Dubose, 1990 April 28; 1 (Box 131)
    - Interview with Dr. John Dow, Superintendent of Schools, 1990 May 3; 2 (Box 132–133)
    - School Planning and Management Team meeting, 1990 May 3; 5 (Box 134–138)
    - Interview with Principal Charles Warner, 1990 May 3; 2 (Box 139–140)
  - Columbia Park Elementary School
    - B-Roll with John Haslinger, guidance counselor, and Mary Whittington, health aide [no audio for first three minutes], 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 141)
    - B-Roll and cafeteria, 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 142)
  - Berkshire Elementary School -- B-Roll and walk through with Rita Robinson, 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 143)
  - Retreat at Eleanor Roosevelt High School, Prince George's County
    - Registration and mixer, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 144)
    - Opening address by Jan Stocklinski and team building led by Sandra Chinn, Human Relations Office, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 145)
    - Workshops
      - "School planning" with Ann Walker, area teacher specialist and Dan Saltrick, assistant superintendent, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 146)
      - "School planning" (continued) and "Creative problem solving" with Charlene Pasco, staff development specialist, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 147)
      - "Creative problem solving" (continued) and "William Wirt: A pilot project" with E. Caldwell, Minnie Pearson, E. Davis, and V. Shaffer, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 148)
      - "William Wirt: A pilot project" (continued), 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 149)
      - "William Wirt: A pilot project" (continued) and "Parent Involvement" with Anne Henderson, director of the National Committee for Citizens in Education's National Information Center, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 150)
  - Prince George's County Comer process retreat -- James Comer's visit, February 14-15, 1990, 1990 October 6; 1 (Box 151)
  - Comer orientation, Yale University, 1992 February 2; 1 (Box 152)
  - Comer premier, 1992 March 9; 1 (Box 153)
  - Comer School Development Program series
    - Segments 4-5, 1992 March 25; 1; videotape (1") (Box 154)
    - Segment 6, parts 1-3, 1992 March 25; 1; videotape (1") (Box 155)
    - Segments 7-9, 1992 March 30; 1; videotape (1") (Box 156)
  - Prince George's County Comer project parent dinner in-service, 1992 June 18; 1 (Box 157)
  - Seventh annual Comer process retreat, 1992 October 24; 1 (Box 158)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 158U)
  - Here, Thayer and Everywhere, "Personalization", 1992 November; 1 (Box 159)
  - Comer Project for Change middle school Planning and Management Team retreat, 1992 November 20-22; 1 (Box 160)
  - Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, "The Comer process: Creating learning communities" [commercially produced], 1993; 1 (Box 161)
  - Here, Thayer and Everywhere, "Student as worker", 1993 February; 1 (Box 163)
  - Leadership development program, 1993 February 1; 1 (Box 164)
  - Here, Thayer and Everywhere, "Integrating", 1993 May; 1 (Box 165)
  - James Comer National Center for Restructuring Education, Schools and Teaching keynote speech, 1993 May; 1 (Box 166)
  - Eighth annual Comer process retreat (Tape 1), 1993 October 2; 1 (Box 167)
  - Eighth annual Comer process back-up copy and breakout session footage, 1993 October 2; 1 (Box 168)
  - Phi Delta Kappa and Agency for Instructional Technology "Reinventing our schools: A conversation with James P. Comer, MD", 1994 February 2; 1 (Box 169)
  - Comer retreat at Eleanor Roosevelt High School, Prince George's County
    - Speakers, 1994 October 1; 1 (Box 170)
    - Mock School Planning and Management Team meeting, 1994 October 1; 1 (Box 171)
  - Principal's Academy -- Principals in residence panel, 1995; 1 (Box 172)
  - Comer retreat
    - Opening session, 1995 October 14; 1 (Box 173)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 173U)
    - a.m. session, "Cast out your nets", 1995 October 14; 1 (Box 174)
    - p.m. session, 1995 October 14; 1 (Box 175)
    - Closing, 1995 October 14; 1 (Box 176)
  - Summit meeting, day one a.m., 1995 November 27; 1 (Box 177)
  - St. Michael's Comer training for demonstration schools, 1996 March 2; 1 (Box 178)
  - New Haven Public Schools reception, Phase 2 -- Valerie Maholmes, Yale University, 1996 April 16; 1 (Box 179)
  - Prince George's County Public Schools -- Comer retreat large group session, 1996 October 19; 1 (Box 180)
  - OP colloquium with Gillette, Graduate School of Applied and Professional Psychology, Rutgers University, 1996 November 25; 1 (Box 181)
  - School Development Conference
    - Tape 1-- 8:30-10:30 a.m., 1997 January 27; 1 (Box 182)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 182U)
    - Tape 2, 1997 January 27; 1 (Box 183)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 183U)
    - Tape 4, 1997 January 28; 1 (Box 184)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 184U)
    - Tape 5, 1997 January 29; 1 (Box 185)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 185U)
    - Tape 6 -- 1:30-2:45 p.m.-- James Comer's address, 1997 January 29; 1 (Box 186)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 186U)
    - Tape 7, 1997 January 31; 1 (Box 187)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 187U)
  - New Haven
    - Tape 1, 1997 March 17; 1 (Box 188)
    - Tape 1, 1997 March 18; 1 (Box 189)
    - Tape 1, 1997 March 20; 1 (Box 190)
    - Tape 2, 1997 March 20; 1 (Box 191)
    - Tape 1, 1997 March 21; 1 (Box 192)
  - Unidentified sessions
    - Morning, 1997 May 5; 1 (Box 193)
    - Late morning and afternoon, 1997 May 5; 1 (Box 194)
    - 1997 May 6, 1 (Box 195)
  - Comer Saw-Me -- Prince George's County Public Schools, Office of Television Resources, 1997 June 23-27; 6 (Box 196–201)
  - School Development Program, 1997 July 16; 2 (Box 202–203)
  - Hartford Club
    - Keynote speaker, 1997 July 17; 1 (Box 204)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 204U)
    - Awards dinner, 1997 July 17; 1 (Box 205)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 205U)
  - Facilitators presentation "School Development Program needs assessment" by Rodney Brown and Shalewa Crowe, Youth Guidance, Chicago, 1997 October 10; 2 (Box 206–207)
  - Comer Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development town meeting, 1997 November 10; 1 (Box 208)
  - Unidentified sessions
    - 8:30-10:00 a.m., 1998 January 26; 1 (Box 209)
    - 10:15 a.m.-12:00 p.m., 1998 January 26; 1 (Box 210)
    - 8:30 a.m-12:00 p.m., 1998 January 27; 1 (Box 211)
    - 1:30-4:30 p.m., 1998 January 27; 1 (Box 212)
    - 8:30 a.m-11:20 a.m, 1998 January 28; 1 (Box 213)
    - 11:20 a.m-3:00 p.m., 1998 January 28; 1 (Box 214)
    - 1990 January 30, 1 (Box 215)
    - 8:30 a.m-12:00 p.m., 1998 February 9; 1 (Box 216)
    - 1:45-5:00 p.m., 1998 February 9; 1 (Box 217)
  - School Development Program thirtieth anniversary symposium
    - "New directions for teacher and administrator preparation", 1998 30 April-1 May; 1 (Box 218)
    - "Systems change in education", 1998 30 April-1 May; 1 (Box 219)
  - Hillary Clinton's speech, 1998 April 30; 1 (Box 220)
  - James Comer at Omni Hotel, 1998 May 1; 1 (Box 221)
  - Thirteenth Comer retreat opening session, Prince George's County Public Schools, 1998 October 10; 1 (Box 222)
  - Developmental Academy -- Middle school children presentation, 1999 March 16; 1 (Box 223)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 223U)
  - Seventh annual Patrick Francis Daly memorial awards for excellence in educational leadership, 1999 July 15; 1 (Box 224)
  - "The importance of child development in education: A conversation with James Comer and Chip Wood", 2000; 1 (Box 225)
  - Comer School Development Program Demo II Weekend at St. Michaels, Prince George's County Public Schools, 2000 February 4-6; 5 (Box 226–230)
  - "Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development-- Comer process: Education, health, and family services, collaborating for children's sake", Undated; 1 (Box 231)
    - Use copy, Undated; 1 (Box 231U)
  - "Comer: Eliminating negative factors which create barriers between home and school and impact on student achievements", Undated; 1 (Box 232)
  - "Comprehensive school reform workshop featuring the school development program, " North Central Regional Educational Laboratory, Undated; 1 (Box 233)
  - "Curriculum in Head Start" and "Individualizing in Head Start", Undated; 1 (Box 234)
  - Edward Joyner power presentation -- Day 2, Undated; 1 (Box 235)
  - "Lunchroom rules," Emma E. Booker, Undated; 1 (Box 236)
  - Newburgh City School District staff development day -- James Comer workshop, Undated; 1 (Box 237)
  - Panel of experienced School Development Program facilitators, Undated; 1 (Box 238)
  - TI-IN Broadcast #7 Jostens, "The Comer Model: A partnership approach to learning", Undated; 1 (Box 239)
  - Tuesday, April 1, 9:30-11:30 a.m., Undated; 1 (Box 240)